纵使细微如蝴蝶之鼓翼 也能造成千里外之飓风 混沌理论
"如果...任何人找到这封信 那就意味着我的计划不起作用
"If anyone finds this, it means that my plan didn't work...
并且我已经死了"
and I'm already dead."
- 埃文？- 应该在这里
- Evan? - I think he's in here.
"如果我能以某种方式回到...
"If I can somehow go back to the beginning...
- 所有这一切的... 开端也许我就能... - 埃文
- of all of this, I might be able... - Evan!
挽救她"
to save her."
埃文
Evan!
《蝴蝶效应》
(十三年前)
埃文
Evan!
我们又要迟到了
We're gonna be late again.
什么时候开始介意准时上学？
When did you ever care about getting to school on time?
家长日要布置教室
We're putting up pictures for parents' night.
别担心 我们还有很多时间
Don't worry, you'll have plenty of time.
爸爸会来吗？
Is Dad gonna come?
你知道答案是什么
You know the answer to that.
他就来一天都不行吗？
Can't he just come out for one day?
你已经问过无数次了
We've been over this 100 times.
这对他来说太危险了
It's too dangerous for him.
可是 兰尼说他爸爸会来
But Lenny said his dad's coming,
汤米和凯丽的爸爸也会来
and Tommy and Kayleigh's dad...
好了 我知道了
Okay, I get the point.
我去也不错呀 是吧？
But I'm not so bad, am I?
是的
No.
好了 祝你一天愉快
Okay, have a great day.
放学我来接你 走吧
I love you. I'll pick you up later. Gotta go.
再见
Bye!
泰瑞博夫人 我得跟你谈谈
Mrs. Treborn, I need to speak with you.
等今天晚上再谈可以吗？我上班已经迟到了...
Can it wait till tonight? I'm late for work and...
我想你真的需要看看这个
I think you really need to see this.
汤米 别惹兰尼
Tommy, leave Lenny alone.
别让我把你送到沃尔特先生的办公室
Don't make me send you to Mr. Voytek's office.
我本来想送到校长那里
I was gonna show this to the principal,
我想应该先与你谈谈
but I thought I should talk to you first.
是什么？
What is it?
昨天我让孩子们画
Yesterday I had all the children make drawings
他们长大了想做什么
of what they wanted to be when they grew up.
多数孩子画的是父母的工作
Most of them made drawings of what their parents did.
但...
But this...
我不懂
I don't understand.
是埃文画的？
Evan did this?
- 能把这个画给我吗？- 当然
- Can I keep this drawing? - Oh, of course.
嗯 还有一件事 泰瑞博夫人
Um, there is one more thing, Mrs. Treborn,
- 提起来就不舒服 - 什么事？
- I feel bad even mentioning. - What?
当我问埃文他的画时
When I asked Evan about the drawing,
他根本就不记得了
well, he couldn't remember doing it.
我不想去？
I don't wanna go.
我不喜欢这个地方 妈妈
I don't like this place, Mum.
恐怖兮兮的
I think it's creepy.
我答应不再画不好的画了
I promise I won't make any bad pictures.
没有事的
You're gonna be fine, okay?
他就是想做一些测试 仅此而已
He just wants to do a couple tests, that's all.
- 哦 - 你会喜欢他的
- Oh. - You'll like him.
很好 做得很好
That's good. You're doing great.
告诉我他没有遗传他父亲的毛病吧
Just tell me he hasn't inherited his father's illness.
我确信检验结果出来时会是阴性
I'm sure the test results will come back negative.
但是你可以做一些其它事情监控他的记忆
But there's something else you can do to monitor his memory.
- 什么事都行 - 写日记
- Anything. - A journal.
让他写下他做过的所有事情
Just have him write down everything that he does.
- 这会有什么作用？- 这样可以刺激他的记忆力
- And what will that do? - It could help jog his memory.
看看第二天他记不记得新东西
See if he remembers anything new the next day.
检验结果几天后出来
These test results will come back in a few days
- 我们会帮你取回来 - 好吧
- and we'll take it from there. - Okay.
"今天妈妈会带我去与凯丽和汤米玩
"Today Mummy is taking me to play with Kayleigh and Tommy.
我会见到他们的爸爸 看看一个真正的爸爸到底是什么样的"
I will meet their father and see what a real dad is like."
太好了 一会儿见
Great, see you soon.
埃文
Evan...
埃文 你拿那把刀干什么？
Evan, what are you doing with that knife?
发生什么了？
What happened?
亲爱的
Honey...
你拿那把刀干什么？
what were you doing with that knife?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
- 你好安德烈 - 乔治
- Hey, Andrea. - George.
你好 小朋友
Hello, little man.
小心走路
Watch your step.
谢谢你 乔治
Thanks, George.
- 没什么 - 这是我医院的电话号码
- Not a problem. - Here's my number of hospital
如果有什么问题 你知道的
in case there are any problems.
请多照顾他 因为...
And please keep an eye on him 'cause...
开玩笑么？
What, are you kidding?
我们今天会玩得非常开心 是不是 小运动健将？
We're going to have a great time today, right, sport?
好吧 乖孩子
Okay, be good, kiddo.
我爱你
I love you.
- 拜 - 再见乔治
- Bye-bye. - Bye, George.
直走 继续 马上到后院去
Go long. Go on. Right in the backyard.
接着
Here it comes.
埃文 你猜怎么回事？爸爸买了新摄像机
Evan, Evan, guess what? Dad got a new video camera
我们要拍电影
and we're all going to be in a movie.
是的 埃文
That's right, Evan.
你可以当明星
And you get to be the star.
我才是明星
I thought I was the star.
嗨 我怎么跟你说的？
Hey, what did I tell you?
现在 埃文
Now, Evan...
你得先答应
You have to promise
打死也不说出去
your bestest, super-duper promise
这是我们的小秘密
that this will be our little secret.
- 你做得到吗？- 嗯
- You think you can do that? - Um-hmm.
这是哪里？
Where am I?
我们这是要干嘛？
Where did we all go?
安静 孩子 站着别动
Calm down, kid, stand still.
刚刚还在别的地方
I was just somewhere else.
怎么来到这里的？
How did I get here?
不要装白痴 否则我要给你妈妈打电话
Quit acting like some damn retard, or I'll call your mother
告诉她你调皮捣蛋得不得了
and tell her what a naughty little shit you've been.
凯丽
Kayleigh...
怎么了？
what happened?
好消息是 结果是阴性
The good news is the results are negative.
没有任何机能障碍
I found no evidence of lesions,
颅腔出血以及肿瘤的迹象
haemorrhaging, tumours.
一定可以查出原因的
But you must have something you can go on.
按我的猜想 失忆和精神压力有关
If I was to guess, I'd say the blackouts are stress related.
可他才七岁啊
But he's seven years old.
七岁的孩子会有什么精神压力啊？
What kind of stress can a seven-year-old have?
很多 比如说没有父亲
Plenty. Maybe he has severe coping problems
也会造成他有这种问题
about not having a father.
你说上次失忆时是
You said the last time the blackouts occurred
跟朋友的爸爸在一起
he was visiting his friend's dad.
他一直催我要见父亲
Well, he has been pushing me to meet his father
- 我却一直拖着 - 值得一试
- and I've been putting it off. - It's worth a shot, Andrea.
我们可以安排一个限制性的会见
We can arrange a controlled meeting.
给詹森适量的镇静剂 多派一些保安
A careful dose of sedatives for Jason, some security,
跟埃文短暂地会见
Evan comes in for a quick visit,
幸许埃文思念父亲的情节
and with a little luck,
也会随之消失
no more missing father complex.
"四月十五号
"April 15th.
今天要见爸爸啦
Today I get to meet my father.
他叫詹森 他是个疯子
His name is Jason and he's crazy.
我希望他能让我管他叫爸爸"
I hope he lets me call him Dad."
(桑尼威尔协会  精神病院)
我爸爸住在这里吗？
You mean Dad lives here?
他不在我们现在所在的这一栋
Not in this wing, actually, no.
如果你见他有点困
Now if your dad seems a little sleepy,
那是因为吃了药 知道吗？
it's because of the medicine, okay?
知道了
Okay.
稍等一会儿就来了
It'll just be a moment, okay?
没事的 我不会咬你
It's okay. I won't bite.
你看过我的照片吗？
You've seen pictures of me, right?
妈妈说我笑起来像你
Uh-huh. Mum says I have your smile
头发也是
and your hair.
- 我要杀了你 - 不
- I will kill you... - Nooo!
他必须死 这是唯一的办法
He has to die! It's the only way!
詹森 住手
Jason, stop!
不
No!
没事了 没事了 没有事了
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be alright.
他伤的很重
He's hurt bad. Get a stretcher.
- 把他拖出去 - 真对不起
- Come on, let's get him out of here. - I'm so sorry.
在生生不息
In sure and certain hope
永恒重生的生命中
of the resurrection to eternal life,
吾等将詹森兄弟交予万能的上帝
we commend to almighty God, our brother Jason.
愿主赐福并接纳他
The Lord bless him and keep him,
愿主的光芒照耀着他
the Lord make his face to shine upon him,
愿主的宽厚仁慈泽被于他
and be gracious unto him
愿主赐予他永恒的安息 阿门
and give him peace. Amen.
(六年之后)
哪去了？它一定在这附近
Come on, where is it? Damn, I know it's down here somewhere.
汤米 烦死了 好了没？
Tommy, I'm bored shitless over here. What's up already?
是啊你到底在找什么呀？
Yeah, what are you looking for, anyway?
闭嘴 笨蛋
Shut up, lard arse. And you, hold your fucking horses.
一定就在这附近
You know, it's here somewhere.
我们还是走吧
We should go soon.
如果让爸爸抓到我们在这里抽烟 我们就死定了
If dad catches us smoking down here, we're dead.
走吧
So let's go.
爸爸有个雷管在这里
I knew Dad had a blockbuster down here!
我们去找个东西来炸个过瘾
Let's blow the shit out of something.
伙计 看你的了
Here you go, buddy.
做梦去吧
What? No freaking way.
- 我可不想碰这种东西 - 你敢不弄试试
- I'm not touching this thing. - The hell you aren't.
要是让别人干的话 你这孬种会去告状的
Any of us does it and you're gonna puss out and nark for sure.
这回不行 你看引信这么短
Ain't gonna work this time, buddy. Look how small this fuse is.
- 我会被炸死的 - 不见得
- I'll get killed. - Not necessarily.
给你
There you go.
这样至少多出个两分钟
It should buy you two minutes at least.
谢谢
Gee thanks, friend.
哎 兰尼 你个笨蛋 只管干吧
Aw, for Christ's sake, Lenny, you moron, just do it.
- 谢谢 - 有种兄弟
- Thanks. - You got balls, man.
够慢的了
Shit took you long enough.
搞什么搞？快点
What the hell? Come on!
埃文 快帮我把他扶起来
Evan, come on. Help me get him up!
埃文 转回身 帮我扶他起来
Evan, get your arse back here and help me get him up.
怎么回事？这是哪里？
What the hell happened? Where are we?
我的天啊我们都做了些什么？
Oh my God. What did we do?
埃文 快来帮我一把
Evan, come on. Help me.
天啊怎么会这样呢？
Oh my God, how could we?
- 快点我们走 - 兰尼你怎么了？
- Come on, let's go! - Shit, Lenny, what happened to you?
他没事
He's fine. He's gonna be okay.
过一会儿都会好的
Everything's gonna be fine.
他怎么了？为啥不说话？
What's wrong with him? Why isn't he speaking?
惊吓过度
He's in shock, ma'am.
到底怎么啦？发生了什么事？
What is it? What happened?
我们在树林里生火
We were just in the woods building a fort
兰尼突然发作 本来好好的
when Lenny freaked out. One minute he was okay,
忽然就一动不动了 是这样的吧 伙计？
and then he just froze up. Right, guys?
到底发生了什么？埃文 告诉我真相
What happened, Evan? The truth.
我不知道 我记不得了
I don't know. I don't remember.
一定有事情发生了 一定有什么事导致这样的
Something must have happened. Something set him off.
我真的一片空白
I blacked it out.
这回你别想再拿你的失忆蒙混过关
Don't try to use your blackouts to get out of this one.
你不是在胡编乱造吧？
You're not making it up?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们晚上一直在观察他
They're keeping him overnight for observation.
嗯
Uh-huh.
我真不知道该拿他怎么办
I just don't know what to do with him.
"我能记起的失忆前的最后一件事
"The last thing I remember before the blackout
就是我把手掩在凯丽的耳朵上
was holding my hands over Kayleigh's ears.
我想我关注更多的是她的手
I think I was more focused on her hands on mine
而不是街对面的信箱
than the mailbox across the street.
妈妈以为催眠会让我想起来"
Mum thinks that hypnosis might be a good way to remember."
什么啊
Damn it.
(死亡证明)
我爷爷也是疯子？
My grandpa is crazy, too?
来 吸气 呼气
Breathe in and breathe out.
放松
And relax.
你已经熟睡
You are completely asleep.
放松
Relaxed.
我想要你领我回到
I want you to take me to the time
你与兰尼在树林里的时光
you were in the woods with Lenny.
把它想像成一部电影
Think of it like a movie.
你可以暂停 重放
You can pause, rewind,
慢放其中的任何细节 只要你愿意
or slow down any details you wish.
你明白吗？
Understand?
是的
Yes.
你现在在哪里？
Where are you now?
我站在凯丽旁边
I'm standing next to Kayleigh.
我的手捂在她的耳朵上
My hands are over her ears.
你在伤害她吗？
Are you hurting her?
不是 我在保护她
No, I'm protecting her.
很好
Okay.
现在我们继续 你看到了什么？
Now let's move forward in time. What do you see?
我看到了一辆车
I see a car.
好的 埃文 告诉我车的情况
Yes, Evan, tell me about the car.
继续
Go on.
没有人会伤害你的
Nothing can hurt you.
记住这只是场电影 你绝对安全
Remember, it's only a movie. You are completely safe.
我不能
I can't...
汽车一瞬间就消失了
The car vanishes and all of a sudden
然后我就躺在树林的地上
I'm on the ground in the woods.
汽车并没有消失
The car doesn't vanish, Evan.
只是你脑中的电影中断了 仅此而已
The movie in your head is broken, that's all.
告诉我汽车的情况
Now tell me about the car.
我不能
I can't!
它开过来了
It's coming...
快点 埃文 快点
Fight it, Evan, hurry.
车开过来了
It's coming!
- 噢我的天啊 - 我数到十你就会醒来
- Oh my God! - On the count of 10,
- 精神焕发 - 你在干吗？
- you'll wake up feeling refreshed... - What are you doing?
记住我和你所说的所有话
and remembering everything that we talked about.
他怎么了？停下来
What is happening? Make it stop!
1 你感觉要醒了 2 你的眼睛不觉得这么沉
One, you're feeling awake. Two, your eyes are not feeling as heavy.
- 5 6... - 快醒来
- Five, six. - Wake up!
- 快点埃文快醒来9 10... - 快让他醒过来
- Come on, Evan, wake up! Nine, 10. - Wake up!
噢 天啊
Oh God.
发生了什么？
What happened?
这个方法起作用了吗？
Did it work?
谢谢妈妈 回头见
Alright, thanks, Mum. See you later.
(《七宗罪》 《阿呆与阿瓜》 上映中)
振作点
Wipe that sad-arse look off your face
不要一脸衰样
before you get us busted.
你看没看到兰尼妈妈看你的眼神？
Did you see the way Evan's mum was looking at you?
对不起
Sorry.
好了
Alright, will someone tell me already
有没有人告诉我那个信箱到底怎么啦？
what the hell happened with the mailbox?
不许再提这件该死的事
Don't you ever bring that shit up again.
永远都不
Not ever!
我们走吧
Let's go.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
噢 真狗屎
Holy shit!
看那个肥佬
Look at that fat fuck!
奶子比兰尼的妈妈还大
He's got bigger titties than Lenny's mum.
- 嘘 - 闭嘴老玻璃
- Shhh! - Shut up, faggot.
谁跟你说话了
No one's talking to you.
对不起 凯丽 真不该来看电影
I'm sorry, Kayleigh, this was a bad idea.
你真的一点都不记得发生什么事了？
You really don't remember anything that happened?
你真幸运
You're so lucky.
所有的事情都会好起来的
Look, everything's gonna be okay.
兰尼也会好起来的 等着瞧吧
Lenny'll be fine. You'll see.
对不起
Sorry.
不是你的错 卡甘夫人跟我爸说
It's not your fault. Mrs. Kagan called Dad
是我们害了兰尼
and blamed us for what happened to Lenny.
你爸把你打成这样？
Your dad did that?
- 就是打得再厉害也不为过 - 说啥呢？
- I deserve a lot worse. - What are you talking about?
他们不配当你爸爸和弟弟
What you deserve is a better father and brother.
他们只会让你觉得自己一无是处
All they do is make you feel like shit.
你真的一点都不知道你有多漂亮？
You really have no clue how beautiful you are, do you?
你他妈的想干嘛？
What the fuck are you doing?!
买爆米花啊你他妈的又想干嘛？
Buying popcorn. What the fuck are you doing?
- 啊噢 - 真不敢想你会这么做？
- Whoops. - I can't believe you freaking did that.
- 你一定要那么讨厌吗？- 管得着
- He's a little punk. - Why are you being such a dick?
那一置信 你都做了什么
I can't believe what you just did.
住手
Stop it!
别打他了
Stop hitting him.
你有什么毛病？
What's wrong with you?
来人帮帮我们啊
Somebody, please help us.
好了 小子 滚出去
Alright, that's it, kid. You're out of here.
滚出去 滚出去
Get him away! Get him away!
现在报道另一则新闻 布雷亚小镇的宁静
Now in another story, the peaceful town of Briarville
今天下午
was rocked this afternoon
被一桩可怕的恶性事件打破了
in the wake of a horrible act of vandalism.
上纽约州警察局认为这只是一起
While police officials in upstate New York believe
单纯的恶作剧 搞过了头
this was a simple act of criminal mischief gone awry,
这个悲剧无疑毁坏了这个社区
the tragedy has clearly devastated the community.
这一灾难性后果主要是由
Now this was the grisly aftermath of a powerful explosion
不明数量的炸药引起的爆炸所造成的
believed to have been caused by an unknown quantity of dynamite.
目前警方还没有发现任何线索 疑犯以及犯罪动机
The police have no leads, no suspects and no motive...
晚安
Good night.
我们搬家吧
We're moving.
连汤米都在生我的气
I can't believe Tommy's still pissed at me.
他知道我们要搬家吗？
He knows I'm moving away, right?
他最近怪怪的
He's been acting real strange lately.
都不正眼看我
He won't even look me in the eyes anymore.
呀 他们来了
Duck, here they come!
你妈妈有没有说过 兰尼已经没事了？
Did your mum say if Lenny was okay?
他肯定好了 他们会放他出来吧？
He must be. I mean, they're letting him out, right?
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
出去透透气吧
I thought you might like some fresh air for a change.
- 汤米跟你们在一起吗？- 没有... 太好了
- Is Tommy with you guys? - No. It's cool.
你在那里面都做了些什么？
So, what'd you do in there?
太可怕了 睡不着
It was awful. You can't sleep because
所有人整晚都在哭喊 尖叫
everybody's screaming all night long.
我再也不想回去了
I never want to go back.
看到没有？
Do you see that?
看到了 怎么会有烟呢？
Yeah, what's up with the smoke?
克罗基特(狗名)
Crockett!
你把我的狗怎么了？
What are you doing with my dog?!
- 这都是你逼出来的 - 你到底有什么毛病？
- Look what you made me do! - What the hell's wrong with you?!
凯丽 天啊醒醒吧
Kayleigh. Oh, God, come on, please wake up.
醒醒吧 快醒醒吧
Wake up, please! Wake up!
为什么不亲她呢 迷人的王子
Why don't you fucking kiss her, Prince Charming?
哦
Ow.
我晕过去多久了？
How long was I out?
凯丽 怎么啦？
Kayleigh, what's wrong?
哦 靠
Oh shit.
(我会回来找你的)
对不起
I'm sorry.
(七年之后)
对不起
Aced it.
好了 时间到 放下铅笔
And time. Put your pencils down
离开前把蓝本子放到我的桌上
and place your bluebooks on my desk before you leave.
纳尔逊先生 你也别写了 我们都在同一个时区
You too, Mr. Nelson. We're all in the same time-zone, here.
做得怎么样 埃文？
So how'd you do, Evan?
不知道 有些名字可能搞混了
I don't know. I might have got some of the stories mixed up.
那个叫狗舔卵蛋的人是巴夫洛夫吧？
Was it Pavlov that conditioned his dog to lick his nuts?
典型的心理学主修生 自以为是
Typical psych major, a complete wise-arse.
研究课题进展得如何？
And how's your project coming?
还想试图改变我们这些谦卑的科学家
Are you still planning to change the way we humble scientists
- 对记忆的看法？- 我还有别的选择吗？
- view memory assimilation? - Don't really have a choice.
天哪 真是混球一个
Oh, jeez, it smells like patchouli and arse in here.
阿里特 这是我彬彬有礼的室友 埃文
Cricket, this is my well-mannered roommate, Evan.
知道了
Yeah...
你就是那个在人类学期末考试时
you're the one that fucked up the bell curve
搞砸别人成绩的人
on my anthropology final.
- 回头见桑普尔 - 再见
- Later, Thumper. - Bye.
- 噢女孩不错老兄 - 给你个内裤
- Wow, sweet girl, man. - I found your shirt, bro'.
变态
Oh, you sick fuck.
好了 穿上衣服 带我出去转转
Alright, man, get dressed. You're taking me out.
什么呀 又想搞一次期中考试又拿A了？
Why, what'd you do, ace another midterm?
不是
No.
比这更好 七年了 没有失忆过
Better than that, seven years, no blackouts.
真是太好了 走 去庆祝一下
Fuck yeah, bro', let's do this!
- 哦耶 - 来啊来啊
- Oh, yeah! - Yeah! Come and get it.
轻一点 刚炒过饭
Be gentle with me! Be gentle! I'm postcoital. I'm tender.
她托着底座猛咬操纵杆？
Did she cradle the balls and work the shaft?
漂亮
Nice.
看 那个蠢家伙
Look at this fucking guy.
来亲我的屁股吧
Get the fuck out of my bar.
对了 你们哪个养了一堆虫子
So, which one of you has the pet worm?
虫子... 精虫
Worms, plural!
那可太多了
Ah. That's so gross.
找他说吧 他有恋虫癖
Talk to him about it. He's got the fetish.
注意 实际上这个心理学项目用来
Watch it. It's a psych project actually.
研究记忆丧失的
It's a study on memory loss.
为我所有刺激和兴奋找到了解释
Better explain before all this excitement gives me a heart attack.
赌十块钱 他能全吃了那些虫子
10 bucks says he eats it off the floor.
如果我能找出
Well, if I can figure out
低等虫子的记忆工作方式
how the memories in a simple worm function,
有助于我了解
it should help me to understand the complexities...
人类大脑的复杂性
of the human brain.
让我打
Let me get this shot.
- 什么他妈的怪胎？- 操...
- What the fuck, weirdo?! - Fuck this...
这可不是你玩的游戏
Well, I guess that's your game.
来 快来
Go, you go.
闻上去像有人在这里做过爱？
It smells like sex in here.
是啊桑普尔今天在这儿搞了一整天
Yeah, Thumper had a busy afternoon.
开玩笑吧 他这么胖
You're kidding? He's so big.
是啊
Yeah.
我猜是超凡魅力的缘故吧 还有就是我自始至终都没有管他
Well, I guess charisma and eyeliner go a long way.
- 要啤酒吗？- 要
- You want a beer? - Yeah.
你这里有没有熏香或者香精蜡烛之类的东西？
You got any incense or scented candles or something?
好了
Okay.
喔 没有
Whoa, no.
不能看
Let me put this away.
好多家伙都把A书藏在床下
Most guys usually tuck porn under their bed.
而你却只有笔记本？
All you've got are comp books?
是的 这些是我的日记
Yeah, they're my journals.
我从七岁就开始写了
I've been keeping them since I was seven.
真的？
Wow.
念点来听听
Read me something.
也许能从中找到一些乐子呢
I ought to be getting something out of this.
这是我想说的
That's all I've got to say.
我们开始
Here we go.
"感觉好像我的大脑拒绝相信我亲眼见到的一切
"It's like my mind refuses to believe what I'm seeing.
听到克罗基特可怖的叫声...
Hearing Crockett make those awful screams.
光写下来就让我浑身颤栗"
Just writing about it gives me the shivers."
继续念
Come on. Go on.
"汤米不知是中了邪还是怎么了
"It was like Tommy was possessed or something.
他的眼睛里充满了仇恨..."
There was a hate in his eyes that..."
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我在哪里？
Where am I?
到底发生了什么？
What the hell's going on?
我打不开啊
I can't get it open!
放下 不然我趁你妈睡觉时割断她的喉咙
Drop it or I'll slit your mother's throat in her sleep.
我抓住汤米了 快救克罗基特
Uhh! I got him, Lenny. Save Crockett!
听我说 埃文 好好听着
Listen to me, Evan, and you listen to me good.
世上的女人成千上万
There's a million other sisters in the world,
为什么你偏要搞我姐姐
so why'd you have to fuck with mine?
没事的 只是一场梦
It's okay. It was just a dream.
呃
Uh-huh...
嗯 不像是一场梦
it didn't feel like a dream.
也许做梦时从不知道那是梦
Maybe because they never do.
那么 帅哥 你每次约会都会昏倒吗？
So, Don Juan, you pass out on all your dates?
兰尼
Lenny...
嘿 给你一个惊喜
hey, I've got a surprise for you.
你猜不到是谁来了
You're never gonna guess who's here.
嗨 是我... 埃文
Hey, it's me... Evan.
你在忙这些... 航模？
What are you working on there? A model?
看来你很忙
Look, uh... I can see that you're busy,
所以我长话短说
so I'll try to make this quick.
还记得
Remember, uh...
小时候
that day at the junkyard
在垃圾场的那天？
when we were kids?
我只是希望你能帮我回忆
I was just hoping that you could help me remember.
一些细节...
Like, just any details about it or...
我割... 不断... 那条... 绳子
I couldn't cut the rope.
嗯
Yeah...
是的 很好
that's good. Um...
还有别的吗？
anything else?
放下 不然我趁你妈睡觉时割断她的喉咙
Drop it or I'll slit your mother's throat in her sleep!
呃
Uh...
老天啊...
Jesus Christ.
它真的发生过
It really happened.
哇喔
Wow, uh...
哇喔 兰尼
Wow, Lenny, l...
不
No
再偷看一眼
Make one peep
我发誓你他妈死定了
and I swear it'll be your last, motherfucker.
"我能记起失忆前的最后一件事
"The last thing I remember before the blackout
就是我把手掩在凯丽的耳朵上
was holding my hands over Kayleigh's ears.
我想我关注更多的是她的手
I think I was more focused on her hands
而不是街对面的
on mine than on the mailbox...
信箱"
across the street."
也许火灭了 谁去查一下？
Maybe it went out, should someone check it?
好的兰尼 你去查吧
Yeah, you do that, Lenny.
再偷看一眼 你他妈就死定了
You make one peep and I swear it'll be your last, motherfucker.
啊
Ugh!
去你的
Fuck!
这是什么？这是什么？
What's this? Huh? What's this?
想要信件吗？
Want to get the mail?
宝贝你还好吗？
How's my sweet girl?
得换尿布啦
You need a change, don't you, honey?
想不想打开？
You wanna open it?
想不想...
- 噢天啊 - 天
- Oh my God! - Holy shit!
快跑
Run!
该死 快走啊
Fuck, Lenny, come on!
兰尼 快走
Lenny, come on!
快点 兰尼 我们走
Come on, Lenny, let's go!
宝贝 这是我的指甲耶
No, baby. That's my finger in your arse.
天啊
Christ, man.
求求你啦... 太残忍了
Fuckin' brutal!
什么？
What the...
- 喂 - 喂是谁啊
- Hello. - Hello. Who is this?
卡甘夫人 我是埃文... 泰瑞博
Mrs. Kagan, um, it's Evan... Treborn.
我希望你知道你把兰尼害成什么样了
I hope you know how much you upset Lenny.
哎呀 真的很抱歉
Yeah, I'm... look, I'm really sorry about that.
我花了一个多小时帮你擦屁股
It took me over an hour to clean up the mess you made.
能让兰尼听电话吗？
Can I just talk to Lenny?
别再打过来了
Don't call here.
妈妈
Mum.
我只是情不自禁 我真为你骄傲
I can't help it. I'm just so proud of you.
爸爸...
Hey, did... did Dad...
詹森成绩好吗？
Did Jason get good grades?
他从来不看书 各科都是A
Please, he got straight As without ever touching a book.
在这方面 他的记忆力从来不出问题
It was the one area his memory never failed him.
他有没有说过什么
Did he ever say that he, like...
在失忆多年以后
figured out a way to recall his lost memories
找到唤起他记忆的方法
like years after he blacked them out in the first place?
- 你问这个干什么？- 没有什么
- Why do you ask? - No, I just figured with him being
我只是想他那么聪明
you know, such a brain and all
可能有办法
it's like, you would think that he would figure out
记起遗忘了的东西
a way to remember stuff that he forgot.
好吧 当他与你一样大的时候
Well, when he was your age...
正值开始思考这些问题的年龄
almost exactly your age come to think of it,
他说他找到了一种方法能够记住他的过去
he said he figured out a way to remember his past.
我分辨不出那是真实的记忆
I couldn't tell if they were real memories
或仅仅是他的想像
or just his imagination.
然后 就在他的病情恶化前...
Then, just before it got so bad, he...
不得不住疗养院前
had to be institutionalised,
他说他能...
he said he could...
什么？
What?
他说他做了什么？
What... what did he do?
忘了它吧
Forget it.
什么都没有过 他那时候已经病得很重了
It's nothing. He was far too sick by then.
妈妈？告诉我到底怎么了
Come on, Mum, what did he say that he could do?
他就像个傻子一样说话
What do you say, as a goof?
告诉我
No, Mum, come on.
蒙蔽自己蛮有趣的
Come on, yourself... it'll be fun.
好吧 你说了算
Alright, it's your dime.
把手给我 年轻人
Give me your hand, young man.
- 这肯定是什么把戏 - 呃
- This is supposed to be your trick. - Uh-uh.
- 艾文 - 什么事？
- Evan! - What?
你原来看过手相吗？
Have you ever had your palm read before?
没有 这是第一次 请温柔一点
No, this is the first time, so be gentle please.
怎么了？
What?
你没有生命线
You have no lifeline.
你不属于这个世界
You don't belong here.
花五块钱就是为了喷你一脸唾沫
For an extra five bucks she'll spit in your face, Mum.
- 不真的他的将来会怎么样？- 他没有灵魂
- No, really, what's his future? - He has no soul!
你根本就不该来到这个世上
You were never meant to be.
精神打击 对吧？
Psychic, huh?
你并不感到奇怪吧
This won't come as much of a shock to you.
- 谢谢 - 不用
- Thank you. - Welcome.
你什么时候又开始抽烟了？
When did you start smoking again?
别管我了 埃文
Lay off, Evan.
嗨
Hey?
怎么了？
What...
你该不会让这个老巫婆败坏一天的兴致吧
You're not gonna let that old hag ruin the rest of our time together?
她在胡说八道 跟疯子一样
She's nuts, she's a lunatic.
就像在演戏
That's like an act.
- 他们这么做是为了... - 我知道
- They just do that... - I know.
她说到了生你的时候
I'm sorry, she just hit a nerve.
为什么？
Well... why?
我搞不懂
I don't get it.
在你出生之前 我怀孕过二次
Before you were born, I was pregnant twice,
都流产了
and they were both stillbirths.
你从来没告诉过我
Why didn't you ever tell me that?
这些都是我不想记得的事
It's not something I like to remember.
当我怀了你的时候 我怕极了
And then when I was pregnant with you,
我必须考虑到最坏的情况
I was terrified. I had to expect the worst.
- 然后呢？- 然后你的出生很顺利
- And? - And you came out fine.
从那个时候开始 我总认为你是我的奇迹小宝宝
And ever since then, I've considered you my little miracle baby.
不要哭
Don't cry.
我们走吧 很晚了
Come on, let's go. It's late.
"反正我不想参加那部电影
"I never wanted to be in the movie, anyway.
天有些冷 因此我想穿上衣服
I was cold, so I wanted to wear my clothes.
可是米勒先生却把我的衬衫脱掉了"
Mr. Miller took my shirt off."
你他妈的在做什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
嘘 做这个时 我需要安静
Shhh, I need quiet for this.
你傻了还是怎么了？
Are you stupid or what, man?
看来你拼命压抑整洁外表下占据着你内心
Maybe there's a reason you repressed the day
的变态心理 也许是有原因的
some pervert had you in your tighty whities.
你做的事我想过两遍了
I'd think twice about what you're doing.
醒来或许情况会更糟
You could wake up a lot more fucked up than you are now.
- 现在我已经搞得够糟了 - 不我...
- More fucked up than I already am? - No, l...
你觉得你了解我？连我自己都不了解我自己
You think you know me? I don't know me!
哇哦
Whoa!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不 是我的错
No, it's my fault.
到他妈该死的哪一天
Can we get through one damn day
你才能不打碎点东西呢？
without you breaking something?
嗨
Hey.
埃文？
Evan.
我的天啊多长时间没见了
Oh my God. It's been a long time.
你好吗？
How you been?
老样子 你知道的
Same old, same old, you know?
不 我不知道 说说你的近况
No, I don't know. Fill me in.
嗯
Uhh, well...
我上了州立大学
I'm going to State now.
一切都还不错 我妈妈也很好
It's going good. My Mum's good.
- 就这样吧 - 抽烟吗？
- I don't know. - You want a smoke?
- 不了大了就不抽了 - 真的？
- No, not since we were kids. - No?
我已经戒了上百次了
I've quit like 100 times.
- 你准备走着回家？- 是的
- Are you walking home? - Uh-huh.
- 我能送你一程吗？- 当然
- Can I walk you? - Sure.
- 真难以相信 - 还有...
- Oh my God. - So...
汤米还好吗？
how's Tommy?
在少年监狱里关了几年 但是...
Well, they kept him in juvie for a few years,
现在 他在Dale汽修厂工作
but now he's working over at Dale's Auto Body.
还不错啊
That's good.
你现在还一直与你父亲生活在一起？
Still living with your dad?
没有
No.
我从十五岁开始便自己谋生了
I emancipated myself at 15.
这需要很多勇气
Must've taken a lot of courage.
如果记得我爸就不会这么说的
Not if you remember my dad.
那你为什么不搬去与你妈妈一起住呢？
Well, couldn't you have just moved in with your mum?
现在她有了新家庭
No, she had a new family.
住不下
Wasn't enough room.
随便啦
Whatever.
这次回来
Well look, the reason I came back to town
就是想与你谈一谈
was to talk to you.
与我？为什么？
To me? Why?
是这样的
Well...
记得小时候
remember when we were kids
我经常失忆吗？
and I used to have those blackouts?
是的 当然
Yeah, of course.
有些记忆我又想起来了
Well, some of those memories have been coming back to me.
我只想跟你谈谈
And I just... I wanted to talk to you
其中一件很特别的事
about one of them in particular.
我会试着回忆下的
Well, I'll try to remember.
我们小时候...
When we were kids, uh...
你爸爸正在拍电影
your dad was making a movie
是关于罗宾汉什么的
about Robin Hood... something.
你想知道什么？埃文
What do you want to know, Evan?!
他... 有没有...？
Is... did he...
在地下室到底发生了什么？
What happened in the basement?
要知道 那是很久以前的事了
Look, it was a long time ago.
我知道
I know.
这就是你为什么大老远跑回来的原因？
Is that why you came all the way back here?
问一大堆关于罗宾汉的愚蠢问题
To ask a lot of stupid questions about Robin Hood?
不 不是的
No, l...
我只是觉得可能发生了一些非常不好的事情
I just think that something really bad might have happened.
你问这有什么目的？
Is there a point to any of this?
不管发生了什么事情 都不是我们的过错
Look, whatever happened it wasn't our fault.
我们只是小孩 我们无需为所做过的事背负什么
We were kids. I mean, there was nothing that we could do to deserve...
闭嘴 埃文
Just shut up, Evan!
你在白费口舌
You're wasting your breath.
你不能因为你父亲扭曲变态而怨恨你自己
You can't hate yourself 'cause your dad's a twisted freak.
你想说服谁 埃文？
Who are you trying to convince, Evan?
你大老远跑回来扰乱我的生活
You come all the way back here to stir up my shit
就因为你不好的记忆
just because you have a bad memory?
你想要的就是让我靠在你的肩上哭泣
What, do you want me to just cry on your shoulder
然后对你说现在一切都很好？
and tell you everything's all better now?
见鬼去吧 埃文
Well, fuck you, Evan!
所有的事情都没变好
Nothing's all better, okay?
所有的事情永远都不会变好
Nothing ever gets better.
要知道 如果我真的那么完美
You know, if I was so wonderful, Evan,
你为什么不打电话给我？
why didn't you call me?
为什么把我留在这里任其腐烂？
Why did you just leave me here to rot?
当他像你这么大时... 就开始想
When he was your age... almost exactly your age, come to think of it
他说他有办法找回以前的记忆
he said he figured out a way to remember his past.
有个家伙给你留了口信了
Some dude left a message for you.
怎么闻起来全是卫生间的味道？
You can smell that all the way to the bathroom.
嗨 埃文 我是卡特教授
Hi, Evan, this is Professor Carter.
我想知道你今天下午为什么没有交论文
I just wondered why you didn't hand in your essay this afternoon.
我很担心 给我打电话 告诉我你什么时间能补上
I was a bit concerned. Call me to schedule a make-up.
你他妈的对我姐姐说了什么？
What'd you say to my sister, motherfucker?
她昨天晚上在电话上跟我哭了一个多小时
Last night she cried on the phone for over an hour to me.
她告诉我你去见过她
She said you came and saw her last night.
她...
She...
她今天晚上自杀了
she fucking killed herself tonight.
她死了
She's dead...
你也会的
and so are you!
(我会回来找你的)
"如果我肚子上的伤疤
"If the scar on my stomach
不是凭空出现的
didn't just come out of nowhere,
也许我父亲并不像大家所认为的那样是个疯子
maybe my father wasn't as crazy as everyone thought.
如果我能制造伤疤 那我有能力治愈伤疤吗？
If I can make scars, do I have the power to heal them?
那凯丽的伤疤又当如何呢？"
What about Kayleigh's scars?"
"反正我不想参加那部电影
"I never wanted to be in the movie, anyway.
天有些冷 我想穿上衣服
It was cold, so I wanted to wear my clothes.
可是米勒先生却把我的衬衫脱掉"
But Mr. Miller took my shirt off."
我有个主意 让我们到地下室去
I've got an idea. Let's go down to the basement.
那里更像个地牢
It'll look more like a dungeon down there.
好了 开点灯
A little light here.
嗯哼
Huh?
嗨 我不是告诉过你把门关上吗？
Hey, now what did I tell you about keeping that door shut?
可是我想看看
But I wanna see.
给你两秒钟 按我说的去做
You're going to see the back of my fist in about two seconds
不然就揍你
if you don't do what I tell you.
好了 这部分的故事是这样的:
Now, in this part of the story,
罗宾汉刚刚与玛丽安小姐结婚
Robin Hood has just married Maid Marian
他们得接吻 还有诸如此类的事
and they have to kiss and stuff,
就像大人那样
like the grown-ups do.
好了 衣服脱掉 凯丽
So, take off your clothes, Kayleigh.
快点啊就像洗澡时那样
Come on, just like when we take a bath.
别大惊小怪的 你也脱 埃文
Don't make a big deal out of it. You too, Evan.
快点 快点 我们在这里拍电影呢
Come on, let's go. Let's go. We're making a movie here.
把你的耳朵捂上
Put your hands on your ears.
现在几点了？
What time is it?
是你该按我说的话去做的时候
It's time for you to do what I tell you to do.
回答错误 老色鬼
Wrong answer, fuckbag!
现在是你认真算计的关键时刻
This is the very moment of your reckoning.
接下来的30秒内 你必须做个选择:
In the next 30 seconds, you're going to open up one of two doors.
第一 你会终身伤害你的亲身骨肉
The first door will forever traumatise your own flesh and blood.
怎么了？
What... what's happening?
你怎么会这么做？
How are you doing this?
它会把你的女儿
It'll change your daughter
从一个美丽女孩
from a beautiful child
变成一具行尸走肉
into an empty shell
她唯一的信任感
whose only concept of trust
被她变态恋童癖的亲生父亲背叛
was betrayed by her own sick paedophile father!
最终
Ultimately...
导致她自杀
it'll lead to her suicide.
- 干得真漂亮老爹 - 你是谁？
- Nice work, Daddy. - Who are you?
别忘了天理昭彰 乔治
Let's just say you're being closely watched, George!
另外一个选择呢 就是
Your other option is to treat Kayleigh like...
当个有爱心的父亲对待凯丽
say like a loving father treats his daughter.
听起来不错吧 老爹？
Sound okay to you, Papa?
是的
Yes.
仔细听我说 老色鬼
Listen close then, fuckbag.
你要是再这样做
You screw this up again,
我发誓我要把你阉了
I'll flat out castrate you.
你要做的就是管好你儿子汤米
What you need to do is discipline your son Tommy,
因为他是个虐待狂
because the kid is one sadistic pup.
最后一件事
One last thing.
永远别再碰我
Don't ever touch me again!
我... 我不会了
I... I won't.
啊
Ahhh!
快一点
Faster, faster!
克罗基
Crockett!
凯莉 没想到你来了
Kayleigh, I can't believe you came!
你钓到鱼了
I think you got one.
看看我的新家
Check out our new house.
- 永远 - 到天荒地老
- Forever. - Hell or high water.
亲爱的 你没事吧？
Honey, are you alright?
天啊埃文 你的鼻子在流血
Oh my god, Evan, you're bleeding.
凯丽 是... 你？
Kayleigh, you're still... You...
噢... 真是不可思议
Incredible.
谢谢 去洗洗干净 再回床上来吧
Well, thanks. Go get cleaned up and come back to bed.
我的衣服呢？
Ohh. Where are my clothes?
不就在那吗 傻子？
Those are your clothes, silly.
卫生间在...
The bathroom is...
快点 我想在上课前化好妆
Hurry up. I want a quickie before school.
什么？
What?
真不敢相信
Unfucking believable.
真不知道你流鼻血也能兴奋成这样
Alright. I wish I could get as excited over a nosebleed.
对不起 我没看到你
Sorry, uh, I didn't see you there.
等等
What?
你就是在酒吧扔爆米花
You're the girl that was with those arseholes
到桑普尔头上的那个女孩
throwing popcorn at Thumper.
什么呀？
What?
你的名字叫格温
And your name is Gwen.
我认识你
I know you.
说真的 埃文 少磕点药
Seriously, Evan, lay off the blow.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
嗨 嗯
Hey, um...
你别生气我问这个
don't freak out when I ask you this, but...
你还记得有一天你爸爸买了架摄像机吗？
do you remember when your dad got that video camera?
怎么了？
What's up, man?
是的 嗯...
Yeah, um...
我记得他
I think he had it like the first day
买来第一天好像就送人了
and then he gave it away or something.
我什么会生气呢？
Why would that freak me out?
我不知道
I don't know.
真是很奇怪
Just being weird.
你还真是个呆子
You are such a goofus.
好吧 晚上见
So I'll see you tonight.
好的
Okay.
- 安德烈 - 埃文
- Andrea... - Evan...
- 恰克 - 我们现在都不在家
- and Chuck... - aren't home right now.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
妈妈
Uh, hey, Mum.
是我 你好 恰克
It's me. And hey, Chuck.
只是问候一声
Ah, I'm just calling to say hi, I guess.
有时间请回电
Give me a call back.
嗨 桑普尔 现在几点了？
Hey, Thumper, do you know what time it is, man?
怎么啦？劳力士丢啦？
What's the matter, you lost your Rolex?
去你妈的 纨绔子弟
Fuck you, frat boy!
各位 记住了
Remember, everyone, there's only two more weeks
还有两周就要交心理学报告
until your psych projects are due.
我说 上星期迟交的
Uh, about that essay I missed last week,
论文能不能给个延期？
we're still okay with the extension, right?
你是？
And you are?
埃文... 泰瑞博
Evan... Treborn.
答案是不行 泰瑞博先生
Well, the answer's no, Mr. Treborn.
赶快坐下考试马上就要开始了
Now please take your seat. The exam is about to begin.
都坐好了
Alright, settle down, everyone.
考试一分钟后开始
The exam will begin in one minute.
别碰我 混蛋
Get off me, arsehole.
是你们先开始的
You guys started that shit.
埃文 干吗抓狂
Evan, you're hysterical.
你复习了吗？
Did you study for this?
哦 呃
Oh, uh...
考完了不就知道了
we'll find out.
我也没复习
Me neither.
妈的 这就是答案？
Holy shit! Are these the answers?
该死 埃文 别吵吵
Damn, Evan, keep it on the dl.
我想明天晚上给凯丽一个特别的惊喜
Hey, uh... I want to do something special for Kayleigh tomorrow night.
因此 如果我开口的话
Uh, so if I said that I needed
你会不会看在兄弟的份上帮我一把？
some help from you and the brothers...
这没问题
I'd say, blow me.
可以找那些入会申请人帮你做啊
Get the pledges to do it.
- 对啊入会申请人 - 嗯
- Right, the pledges. - Yeah.
可以答题了
You may begin now.
噢 真是太棒了
Oh, that was so good.
噢 天啊
Oh my God.
那里学来的新花招？
Where'd you learn those new tricks?
怎么了？
Why?
是不是很奇怪？
It... it wasn't weird, was it?
是的 如果你认为多次高潮是很奇怪的话
Yeah, if you call multiple orgasms weird.
喂
Hello?
- 别管它 - 喂？
- Fuck 'em. - Hello?
哦
Oh.
你说我们为什么...
What do you think it is about us
这么般配？
that makes us so perfect?
我是说
I mean...
为什么我搬走后
why did you sneak out
你还偷偷溜出来找我？
to visit me after I moved away?
因为我想你
'Cause I missed you.
你认为我爸爸会阻止我与你见面？
What, do you think my dad could have stopped me from seeing you?
他能把我怎么样？
What's he gonna do?
噢 我的脚趾麻了
Oh, my gosh. My toes are numb.
你觉得我们会永远在一起吗？
Do you think that we'll be together forever?
那是我们的计划 不是吗？
That is the plan, isn't it?
不管天荒地老
'Hell or high water'?
嗯
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, that's...
我只是想再确认一下
I was just making sure.
是啊就是这个计划
Yeah, that's the plan!
好啦
Alright, uh...
各位已经清楚要给我干什么了吧？
all you rushes, you know what you have to do for me.
入会申请人
Pledges, uh...
我们都是入会申请人 先生
we're pledges, sir.
埃文兄弟 不 是先生
Uh, brother Evan, sir.
别在那儿逗了
Are you kidding me?
什么？你刚才跟我说什么？
What? What did you say to me?
给我背一遍希腊字母表 背啊
You know what, give me the Greek alphabet. Give it to me!
- 阿 - 阿
- Uhh-uhh. - Uhh-uhh.
- 阿尔法贝塔... - 阿尔法贝塔伽马德尔塔...
- Alpha, beta... - Alpha, beta, gamma, delta...
伊普西龙 截塔 艾塔 西塔 约塔 卡帕 兰布达 缪 纽 克西
epsilon, zeta, eta, theta, iota, kappa, lambda, mu, nu, xi,
奥密克戎 派 肉 西格马 套 宇普西龙 西 普西 欧米伽 先生
omicron, pi, rho, sigma, tau, upsilon, phi, chi, psi, omega, Sir.
也许这么说才对 不许这样看着我 低头
Maybe that's what it is. Don't fucking look at me, look down.
啊呵
Uh...
好了
alright, um...
你们这些申请入会的
so, you... you pledges
兄弟知道该为我做什么了
you guys know what you need to do for me.
你们都去冲个澡
And you guys take a shower
如果有人想找麻烦
and if anyone gives you any trouble,
告诉他们我说了算
you tell 'em I said it was okay.
什么？
What?
冲澡 臭娘们
Shower that, bitch.
你这是要带我去哪里？
I don't understand. Where are you taking me?
不告诉你
I'm not telling.
我的天啊
Oh my God!
哇喔 真是太漂亮了
Wow, it's beautiful.
请坐这里
Go on, sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
为什么对我这么好？
Why are you doing this for me?
今天早晨醒来的时候
When I woke up this morning...
我见到你的笑容
I saw your smile.
就是这种笑容
That smile.
于是我知道
And I knew
我的余生要与你
that I wanted to spend the rest of my life
共度
with you.
老兄 到处找你
I've been looking all over for you, man.
有人砸了你的车
Someone trashed your car.
天啊
What the...
这是谁干的？
Who did this?!
谁干的？
Who did it?!
也许是那帮贝塔帮的混蛋
It was probably those Beta fuckers.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
就在我们会馆前面
How did somebody get away with this
谁跑得掉？
right in front of the frat house?
- 什么东西狗项圈？- 是汤米
- Dude, what is that, a dog collar? - Tommy.
别这样
Don't.
也许他正看着呢
He might be watching.
是我的错
It's my fault.
我该早点告诉你他几周前就被释放了
I should have told you he was released a few weeks ago.
是的 那会好很多
Yeah, it might have been nice.
天呐
God.
希望这个能临时救一下急
Like this is gonna do any good.
也许弟兄中有人有枪
Maybe one of the frat guys has got a gun.
埃文 你开什么玩笑？
Evan, don't even joke!
他不会伤害你的
He's not going to hurt you, okay?
他只是想把你从我身边吓走
He's just trying to scare you away from me.
他杀了我的狗
He killed my dog.
- 你不记得了？- 埃文那不是他的错
- You don't remember that? - Evan, it's not his fault.
你知道他从小就饱受虐待
You know how bad he had it when we were kids.
不 别跟我说他小时侯有多么可怜
Oh no, don't give me this bad upbringing shit.
你不是变得很好吗？
You turned out just fine.
我父亲从来不伤害我
My father never laid a hand on me.
他把对我的气都发泄到汤米身上了
It's like that prick saved it all up for Tommy.
好吧
Okay. Alright. Uh...
让校园警卫去处理吧
We'll let campus security deal with it. Okay?
我想自己一个人睡
You know what? I think I should sleep alone.
不 你不能一个人 我要与你在一起
No, you're not staying alone. I'm staying with you.
埃文 我只是不想让汤米在这个时候看到
Evan, I just... I don't want Tommy
我们在一起
to see us together right now.
不 我已经失去过你一次 我不想再失去你
No, I lost you once and I'm not losing you again.
你说失去过我一次是什么意思？
What do you mean you lost me once?
你从来都没有失去过我 你在说什么？
Evan, you've never lost me. What are you talking about?
你最近总是怪怪的
God, you've been acting so weird lately.
车子刚被砸 是有点怪
Look, my car just got wrecked, okay? I'm kind of freaking out.
我知道这点 但是...
I know that, but...
你的口音变了
your accent's changed.
- 就连走路的姿势也不一样了 - 走路不一样？
- You don't even walk the same. - What, I walk differently?
我是说今天晚餐
I mean, that dinner tonight,
你是如此帅气迷人
it was so beautiful. It was gorgeous.
可让人感觉好像不是你
But it just wasn't you.
我只是想对你好点
I can't do something nice for you?
等等
Wait...
那不是你的夹克吗？
isn't that your jacket?
汤米
Tommy!
你这个变态 离我们远一点
You stay away from us, you sick fuck.
什么叫做狗屁的"我们"
Oh, get this "us" shit.
好象我会伤害我亲姐姐一样
Like I'd ever lay a hand on my own sister.
你对自己还真是好
You're doing real nice for yourself, Evan.
你有很好的生活
You've got a nice life,
有很好的朋友
you got nice friends,
更别提还搞上了我姐姐
not to mention you're fucking my sister.
她长得还真不赖
Not a bad piece of arse if I say so myself.
- 住嘴汤米 - 好了好了这是在恭维你
- Shut up, Tommy! - Oh, come on. That's a compliment.
那你到底想干嘛？想怎样？
What are you doing, man? What the fuck?
全世界爱你还不够
Oh, it's not good enough that the whole fucking world loves you?
你还要抢走这世上唯一
But you've got to take the only thing on this Earth
不把我当成一堆狗屎的人
that doesn't think that I'm a piece of shit?
汤米 你知道我是爱你的
You know I love you.
而且没人把你当成一堆狗屎
No one thinks that you're a piece of shit, Tom.
噢是吗？你管我叫什么来着？我想是... 变态
What was it you said? I think I believe it was, "sick fuck"!
汤米 不要 汤米
Don't! Tommy!
住手
Stop!
不 住手 天啊
Stop! Oh my God!
住手
Stop!
住手 天啊
Oh my God!
哦
Oh!
不要 埃文
No, Evan!
住手
Stop!
- 快住手你会杀了他的 - 妈的他疯了
- Stop it! You're gonna kill him! - He's a fuckin' maniac!
不要这样 我求你了
Don't do this, I'm begging you!
是你毁了兰尼的生活
You ruined Lenny's life!
你杀了克罗基特
You killed Crockett!
你杀了那个女的和她的孩子
You killed that woman and her baby!
现在你又想杀了我
Now you're trying to kill me.
你他妈还想杀我
Just tryin' to fucking kill me!
天啊
Oh my God!
天啊你做了什么？
Oh my God, what did you do?
天啊
Oh my God!
你在那里 肥猪
You right there, faggot!
第一次进来？
First time?
是的
Yeah.
最好别被当成女人
You'd better not bitch up, man.
不然你会被蹂躏得很掺
You'll wind up someone's luggage that way.
你可以保护我吗？
Can you protect me?
就算是耶稣
Jesus himself
我也不会帮他挡那帮兄弟的
couldn't make me stand up against the brotherhood.
听着 小子
Look, man...
他们来的时候
when they come,
脑袋里尽量想点别的
you go someplace else in your head, man.
只想成是在别的地方撒尿
Be somewhere else.
到后面去 混蛋
Back your arse up.
把那个给我
Yo, gimme that.
我跟你的律师谈过了
I spoke to your lawyer.
嗯 她确信
And he says he's sure
能用"正当防卫"帮你脱罪
he can get you off on self-defence.
所以你只要耐心一点
So if you're just patient...
妈妈
Mum...
我要在这里呆多久？
How long am I gonna be in here?
我不知道
I don't know.
这种事情需要时间的
These things take time.
日记呢？
What about the journals?
我要的那些你带来了吗？
Did you bring the ones I asked you to bring?
我只找到了这两本
I found these two.
别的还在储藏室
The others are still in storage.
妈妈 我...
Mum! L...
我需要全部的日记
I need them all,
全部的
all of them.
我会都拿来给你的
And I'm going to get them to you,
但是 现在 你得集中精力在案子上
but right now, you need to concentrate on the case.
拜托
Please.
好吧
Alright.
你说得对
You're right.
凯丽怎么样了？
What about Kayleigh?
她还好吗？
Is she alright?
对她说我很抱歉
Try to tell her I'm sorry.
时间到了
Time's up.
我不会再失去你的
I'm not going to lose you, kiddo.
答应我 撑下去
Promise me you'll hang on.
舔我的下面呢 还是想吃我的刀子？
Shit on my dick or blood on my knife.
那是我的
They're mine...
快啊
Come on!
后退 快退后
Back the fuck off!
演出结束了 女士们
Show's over, ladies!
把这条蛆虫关回牢房
Put this maggot back in his cell.
快 我们走
Move it! Come on, let's go!
今天晚上见 小宝贝
We'll be seeing you later on tonight, little sister.
"今天
"Today, I found
我找到了爷爷的死亡证明
my grandfather's death certificate.
他和我父亲一样死在精神病院
He died in a nut house just like my father.
妈妈不承认 但她认为我的下场会和他们一样"
Mum denies it, but she thinks I'm going to end up the same way.
哈哈哈
Boo-hoo-hoo.
快点 快点
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
快来 Reese
Come on, Reese.
你信教 卡洛斯
You're religious, Carlos,
你是不是很相信
you believe in that whole bit,
"上帝神秘行事"？
the Lord works in mysterious ways?"
有话直说 老弟
Straight up, man.
我相信耶稣送我到你牢房是有原因的
'Cause I think Jesus sent me to your cell for a reason.
是要你帮助我
For you to help me.
什么屁话
Shit.
我知道你疯了
I knew you were crazy, man.
我没有胡说
I ain't bullshitting you.
耶稣给我托梦了
Jesus speaks to me in my dreams.
哎哟 是吗？
Oh, yeah?
那可真酷啊
That's cool. Great.
赌一根烟 我就能证明给你看
A pack of smokes says I can prove it to you.
现在看仔细我的手和脸
When I'm out, I need you to watch my hands and face closely.
你需要看监狱心理医生了
You need to see the prison shrink, man.
告诉我有没有看到奇怪的事情
Just tell me if you see anything just... weird.
会比现在还奇怪？
Weirder than this?
可能是一个记号 也可能是个疤痕
It could be marks. It could be scars.
可能是任何东西 我也不清楚
It could be anything, I don't know.
"星期三 一张莫须有的画给我带来了麻烦
"On Wednesday, I got in trouble for a drawing I didn't do.
妈妈不让我看这张画"
Mummy won't let me see it."
别像猴子一样到处跑 埃文 坐下 把画画完
Hey, no monkey business, Evan. Sit down and finish your drawing.
大家都不错
That's great, everyone.
尽管想像你们将来想做什么样的人
Just imagine what you want to be.
没有任何限制
There's no limits.
博斯韦尔夫人
Oh, Mrs. Boswell.
天啊奇迹啊
Sweet Jesus, it's a miracle!
看看你手上的记号
Look, it's stigmata, man!
看到什么了？这像什么？
What'd you see? What'd it look like?
主的记号 无中生有
The signs of the Lord, man. They just come out of nowhere.
我还以为
Man, I thought you were...
你他妈是个疯子呢？
I though you were fucking crazy, man.
这回你相信我了吧？
So now you believe me.
有话直说 老弟
Straight up, man.
我们做个交易吧
Wanna make a deal?
听我说 我是新来的
Alright, look. I'm new here,
我想我已经了解了这里的情况
but I think I get how things work.
要么加入帮派 要么就死
You either join a gang or you're dead.
我可不会与黑鬼为伍
Well, I sure as fuck ain't joining up with no spics or niggers.
我又不想死
And I don't want to die.
所以...
So...
我该怎么办？
what do I gotta do?
我是新来的 我得自己想办法生存
I'm the new guy. I've got to work my way up, so...
所以...
should I...
是不是要我现在就吸吮你下面？
suck your dick now...
还是...
or...
你的血统... 纯正吗？
Is your blood pure?
我不是他妈的犹太佬
Well, I ain't no fucking kike,
你是指这个吧？
if that's what you're asking me.
那好吧 就试试你的本事了 宝贝儿
Well then, let's see what you got, honey.
牙齿还想要的话 就得给我小心点
Watch the fucking teeth or you'll be leaving without 'em.
是的 先生
Yes, Sir.
到爹地这儿来吧
Come to daddy.
"我们穿过树林来到垃圾场
"We took the woods behind the junkyard
以免遇见汤米
just to make sure we wouldn't bump into Tommy!
我们还没有看到烟雾..."
We hadn't seen the smoke yet."
挡住他们
Hold 'em. Hold 'em.
"我们穿过树林来到垃圾场
"We took the woods behind the junkyard
以免遇见汤米
just to make sure we wouldn't bump into Tommy.
我们还没有看到烟雾..."
We hadn't seen the smoke yet."
好的 你个狗日的畜生
Rot in hell, you fucking animals!
等一下
Wait, before we...
我们先得找个能把袋子打开的东西
we need something that could open the sack.
我希望你用这个 兰尼
I want you to take this, Lenny.
今天就是你的救赎日
Today's your day of atonement.
我知道 对于那个妇女和孩子你有多内疚
I know how guilty you feel about that woman and her baby.
埃文 别说了 现在不是说这个的时候
Evan, stop it. It's not the time.
不 这是唯一的机会了 今天是你拯救自己
Now's the only time! Today you get a chance to redeem yourself,
洗新革面的机会
to start all over with a clean slate.
- 你在说些什么呀？- 埃文你是不是疯了？
- What are you talking about? - Evan, you're acting crazy.
拜托 以前你可以信任我 这一次你也要信任我
Please, if you've ever trusted me before, trust me on this one.
把绳子割断
Cut the rope.
跟我来
Come on.
- 好好听着埃文 - 你要啥我就干啥
- Listen to me good, Evan. - I'll do whatever you want.
你不想让我再见凯丽 没问题
You don't want me to see Kayleigh ever again, fine.
只要放过克罗基特
Just let Crockett go.
另外 你现在杀了它
Besides, if you kill him now,
你肯定会被送到少年监狱
they'll stick you in juvie for sure.
我知道你从来不会丢下你姐姐给你老爸吧
And I know you'd never leave your sister alone with your father.
兰尼 不要
Lenny, no!
哦 天呐
Oh God.
哦天哪 兰尼
Oh God, Lenny.
我说砍断那绳子
I said cut the rope.
看来又倒回来了
It's all backwards.
啊啊啊
Ah! Ah! Ah!
艾文
Evan...
这是哪门子怪事？
What the fuck?
兰尼 不要
Lenny, no!
想搭一程吗？
Want a ride?
兰尼
Lenny!
快打911
Somebody call 911!
埃文 埃文 埃文
Evan! Evan! Fuck! Evan!
嗨 医生
Hey, doc.
伤得怎么样？
What's the damage?
- 我还能活多久？- 好好说话埃文
- How much time do I got? - Cute, Evan.
有点复杂 我从来没有见过类似的结果
It's a little complicated. I haven't seen results like these before.
比我爸还复杂？
Not even with my father?
实际上 20年前没有这种检验
Well, actually, they didn't have these tests 20 years ago.
那么你有什么发现？
So, what did you find?
我们发现了大部分的出血都来自这里 大脑外层的大部分
We're finding most of the haemorrhaging is coming from here,
也就是大脑皮层
the outer layer of the cerebral cortex.
人的记忆就是储存在那里的 妈妈
That's where the memories are stored.
- 谢谢你埃文 - 嗯哈
- Thank you, Evan. - Uh-huh.
我从来没有见过类似的东西
I've never seen anything like it.
我们把它跟去年的比较
We compared these to the ones taken last year.
我们发现了严重的出血和大量神经重构
We found severe haemorrhaging and massive neural reconstruction.
那么这个对于埃文来说 意味着什么？
What does that mean for Evan?
妈妈 他说的是
What he's saying, Mum, is that I've jammed
我的大脑一年之内塞进了四十年的记忆
40 years worth of memories into my head in the last year.
超额吸收 好象重灌大脑程序
It's overload city. I've completely reprogrammed my brain.
- 是这样的吗？- 是的
- That about the gist of it, doc? - Yeah.
我出去在车里等
Alright, I'm going to go wait in the car.
这里的灯光太刺眼
The light in here is kind of bugging my eyes, so...
见到你很高兴 医生
It was good seeing you, doc. It really was.
这真的... 真的是让我大长见识
It was very... very informative.
看来我得找人
But, you know, I got people to see
多要点东西来读
and things to read.
好的 再见
Alright, see ya.
嗨
Hey.
是我
It's me...
埃文
Evan.
需要什么东西吗？
Can I get you anything?
那... 那些
What about... what about some of those
你喜欢的航模吧
model airplanes you like, huh?
我想你很久
I bet I can get a shitload
没看到航模在飞了
of those model airplanes up in here.
兰尼
Lenny.
你一直都知道 是不是？
You knew the whole time, didn't you?
当你把那个利刃放在我手里的时候
When you put that shard in my hand...
你就知道会有大事发生
you knew something big was going to happen.
是不是？
Didn't you?
是的
Yeah...
- 我知道 - 那么现在躺在这里的应该是你
- I knew. - Then you should be where I am.
躺在这里的
You should be
应该是你
where I am.
"今天我要去见我的父亲
"Today I get to meet my father.
他的名字叫詹森
His name is Jason...
是个疯子
and he's crazy.
我希望他能让我管他叫爸爸"
I hope he let's me call him Dad."
你没事吧？你刚才
You okay? 'Cause you look like
看起来好像走了神
you went somewhere else there for a second.
听着 詹森 我要去
Look, Jason, I need some fast answers from you
纠正我做过的事 请给我简明的信息
if I'm ever gonna fix what I've done.
我希望诅咒随我一同消失
I was praying this curse would have ended with me.
但是没有
Yeah, but it didn't.
我现在需要的是能把它们改正过来的信息
So now I need information to make things right again
你是唯一能告诉我的人
and you're the only one that can give it to me.
根本就没有什么正确可言
There is no right.
你不可能做到改变一个人 而又不毁掉那个人
You can't change who people are without destroying who they were.
谁说不能把事情改得好一点？
Who says you can't make things better?
你不能充当上帝 儿子
You can't play God, son.
事情到我应该了结了
It must end with me.
再这样下去 你可能会杀了你和你妈妈的
Just by being here you may be killing your mother.
你说的都是废话
That's bullshit, you know?
等所有事情搞定后 我会给你寄张明信片来
I'll send you a postcard when I made everything perfect again.
不 不
Ahh! No, no!
刚出来是吗？
Just get out, did ya?
嗯
Hmm?
没什么 我兄弟关了一阵子后
Oh, nothing, just that my brother did a stint in the pen
也是这样吃东西的
and he used to eat like that.
我家人口众多
I come from a big family.
我没有恶意
Well, I meant no offence.
当然
None taken.
嗨
Hey, uh...
凯丽·米勒还在这里上班吗？
Does Kayleigh Miller still work here?
对不起 从来没有听说过这个人
I'm sorry. I never heard of her.
真他妈的见鬼 连在自己家都得不到片刻安宁
God! Can't a man get a little goddamned peace in his own house?!
你不会是来这儿卖饼干的吧？
I don't suppose you're here to sell cookies?
猜得好 你这个该死的混蛋
Good guess, fuckbag.
还记得我吗？
Remember me, huh?
七岁那年我们聊过一次
We had a nice chat once when I was seven.
有个问题要问你
I got one question for you.
到哪里才能找到你女儿？
Where can I find your daughter?
噢 还以为是别的什么人呢
Oh, I thought you were someone else.
快点说 我在等人来
Make it fast, I'm expecting someone.
嗨 见到你真好
Hey. It's good to see you.
我能进来吗？
Can I come in?
要是知道你来的话
If I knew you were coming,
我会好好打扫这个鬼地方
I would have cleaned the stains off the sheets.
你来想干什么？
What do you want?
就是想见见朋友 老朋友
I just needed to see a friendly face.
时间就是金钱 埃文
Well, time is money, Evan.
钱在这儿
Money.
该给老朋友十分钟 对吧
I guess I can spare 10 minutes for an old friend, right?
那... 你想来点什么花招？
So, how's tricks?
对不起 职业幽默
Sorry, occupational humour.
我能明白
I got it.
你别干了
You can stop now.
噢 对不起
Oh, sorry.
是不是我从事的职业让你不舒服了 宝贝儿？
Does my line of work make you uncomfortable, precious?
不是 但不要拿这个来伤害我
No, just that you felt like you had to use it to hurt me.
我去了你过去呆过的地方
I've been where you've been.
哈
Ha!
那是哪里啊？
Where is that?
如果我告诉你 你不会相信我的
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
人们总是这么说"你不会相信我的"
I know people always say that,
但我的状况真的很难说清楚
that you wouldn't believe me,
甚至不值得努力
but in this case it's not even worth trying, so...
我不知道你在哪
I knew I needed to find you,
所以去逼你爸告诉我
so I went over to your dad's
你的住址
and made him tell me where you were.
然后来到这里
Then I came here and the rest you know.
你是对的 我不信你
You're right, Evan, I don't believe you.
我从没想过你会相信
I never thought you would.
正因为这样 之前我就从没有告诉过其他人
That's why I never bothered to tell a soul until now
以后也不会
and I never will again.
我是你唯一告诉过的人？
I'm the only person you've told?
这也太扯了吧
That's a great line.
其他女人听了也这么亢奋？
Does that make other girls wet?
她们真的会相信这些屁话？
Do they actually eat up that bullshit?
不管你相不相信
You know, I could give a shit whether you believe me or not.
老实说 我懒得证明给你看
Frankly, I'm too tired to prove it to you...
噢 还有得证明啊？
Oh, there's proof now, huh?
我怎么知道你大腿内侧有颗痣
How else would I know you have twin moles on your inner thigh?
来花过50块钱的人都可以告诉你
Anyone with 50 bucks could tell you that.
好的
Okay.
这个不算
Forget that.
我知道你更喜欢
How about the fact that you prefer
臭鼬的味道胜过花香
the smell of skunk to flowers?
还有 你讨厌胡荽
Or that you hate cilantro
因为由于某些你自己不知道的原因
because for some reason unknown to you
它让你想起了你的异父姐妹
it reminds you of your stepsister?
还有 你高潮时脚趾会发麻
Or that when you have an orgasm, your toes go numb?
我确信你所有的嫖客都知道这些
I'm sure all of your clientele are privy to that.
你知道 我想你应该知道
You know? Look, I just thought you should know.
知道什么？
Know what?
你和我曾经有过一段
That you were happy once...
快乐时光
with me.
你知道 你的故事里有一个大漏洞
You know there's one major hole in your story.
我他妈打死也不可能
There's no fucking way on this planet
参加什么他妈的姊妹会
or any other, I would ever be in some fucking sorority!
那时你确实很快乐
You were happy there.
噢 你哭了
Oh, you're crying?
你的钱包不要了？
You sure you don't want your wallet?
不要 我要去的地方不需要它
No, I don't need it where I'm going.
再次改变他人的生活 是吗？
What, are you off to change everyone else's life again? Is that it?
也许下次你会现身某处豪宅
Maybe next time you'll pop up in some mansion
而我却在提华纳象头驴一样累死
while I end up in Tijuana doing some donkey act.
你知道吗 我受够了
You know what? I'm over it.
每次想帮忙
Every time I try to help someone
结果越帮越忙
everything just goes to shit.
不要灰心 小滑头
Well, don't give up now, slick.
你已经为我做了这么多
Hell, you've already done so much for me.
你为什么不及时回去
Why don't you go back in time
救哈波恩夫人和她的孩子
and save Mrs. Halpern and her baby?
兰尼也就不会突然发疯从而毁了我的家庭
And then maybe Lenny wouldn't freak out and ruin my family.
不 回到我七岁的时候吧
No, go back to when I was seven
在我爸爸的的摄像机前操我
and fuck me in front of my daddy's video camera.
挽救我不幸的童年吧
Straighten me out a bit.
别在我床上搞 滚开
You're on my bed. Get out!
不是可以的吗？干吗大惊小怪
Buddy, I thought it would be okay what with you being sick and all.
我不想说第二遍了
I'm not going to say it again.
"我只记得失忆前
"The last thing I remember before the blackout
我把手掩在凯丽的耳朵上
was holding my hands over Kayleigh's ears.
我心里关注更多的是她放在我手心上的手
I think I was more focused on her hands on mine
而不是街对面的信箱"
than on the mailbox across the street."
女士退后 别靠近那个信箱
Lady, stay back! Don't go near the mailbox!
- 白痴 - 快后退
- Idiots! - I mean it, woman! Get the hell back!
我来救你
I'll save you, lady!
见鬼 我不是已经叫你们俩个出去吗？
God damn it, I thought I told you two to get out.
对不起 吵醒你了吧？
Oh, sorry, man. Did we wake you?
不是 太酷了
No, it's cool.
好吧
Okay.
真是太酷了
It's really cool.
这是他妈怎么回事？
What the fuck is this?
- 求你保住他的胳膊 - 能打开柜子吗？
- Please save his arm! - Can you open up my locker?
- 生日快乐 - 我也能来吗？
- Happy Birthday! - Can I come too?
爆米花要移开吗？
Do you want me to hold your popcorn?
伊凡 拿条毛巾来
Evan? Get a towel! Get a towel!
埃文 天呐
Evan! Oh my God!
埃文
Evan! Evan! Evan!
凯丽 你去哪？
Hey, where you going?
你的笑容好美 我爱她的微笑
You ever notice Kayleigh's smile? I love her smile.
兰尼是最好的
Lenny's the best.
你们是最速配的一对
You guys make a great couple.
你觉得有人会爱我吗？
You ever think that I'll find someone?
埃文
Evan!
我们这是要去哪？
Where are we going?
送你去医院
We're taking you to the hospital, Evan.
- 不送我回去 - 你妈妈会杀了我的
- No, take me back. - Sorry, your mum would kill me.
- 哦 - 你带我回去兰尼
- Oh. - You take me back, Lenny!
你欠我太多了...
You owe me that much.
看什么看？无聊
What are you geeks looking at?
很得意 是吧？一群他妈的失败者
It must be nice to be so goddamed perfect, huh?
兰尼来帮我一把
Fucking losers! Lenny, help me!
先帮他翻过身来 先翻过身来
Here, get him over. Get him over.
嗨 布莱恩 脑袋感觉如何啊兄弟？
Hey, Brian, how's your head feeling, buddy?
我看见了你带回家的那个女孩
I saw that girl you went home with.
今天早晨她借没借你的剃须刀用？
Did she borrow your razor this morning?
别胡说
You're so bad.
嗨 汤米来了 嗨 汤米 汤米
Hey, there's Tommy. Hey, Tommy! Tommy!
嘿 怎么样了 伙计们？
Hey, what's up, guys?
嗨 兄弟 我按你说的做了
Hey, man, I did what you said.
基金有着落了
We're pooling our student funds with the Hillel house
即将办舞会
and we're having an awareness dance.
真是太好了 也许我可以大跳轮椅舞
Oh, awesome. Maybe I can spin my chair around
跳到吐出来为止
to a techno remix of 'Hava Nagila' till I puke.
现在 我们该去教室了
Maybe we should be getting to class now.
现在上心理学课又有什么用呢？
What's the point of psych class now?
明天醒来也许发现自己在孟加拉一个肮脏的农场
Tomorrow I could wake up a dirt farmer in Bangladesh.
来我推你去散散步
Let's go for a stroll.
拜 宝贝
Bye, babe.
- 嗯 - 拜老姐
- Yippee. - Bye, sis.
他怎么了？
What's up with him?
看来 汤米现在是典型的信教爱国好青年
So Tommy's really into this Jesus freak thing, huh?
你知道 自从他救了哈波恩夫人与孩子后
You know how spiritual he's gotten
他的精神得到从来没有的升华
ever since he saved Mrs. Halpern and Katie.
他救了哈波恩夫人？
He saved Mrs. Halpern?
真他妈可笑 就凭这人？
Please. The twisted fuck.
埃文 我们在这儿歇会儿
Here, why don't we sit right here?
来点燕麦卷吗？
Want a granola bar?
来拿着
Here, just...
看来 我该修理它了
Yeah, I gotta fix these things or something.
凯丽
Kayleigh...
你有没有想过我们之间的事？
do you ever think about us?
我的意思是... 你是否曾经想过
I mean, do you ever wonder
我们之间的事情会完全不同？
if things might have been different between us?
当然 埃文
Sure, Evan.
你是第一个我真正曾经在乎的人
You were the first person I really ever cared about.
- 曾经？- 是的
- I was? - Yeah.
那就是我小时候不去与我妈妈一起生活的原因
That's why when I was little, I never went to live with my mother.
我不明白
I don't get it.
当我的家庭破裂的时候
When... when my folks split up,
他们让我和汤米选择想跟谁一起生活
they gave me and Tommy a choice of who we wanted to live with.
实际上我不能忍受我爸爸
And I couldn't stand my dad.
但是我知道如果我搬去妈妈生活在一起
But I knew that if I went to move with my mum,
我就再也见不到你了
I'd never see you again.
这些我都不知道
I didn't know that.
这么说 你还一直在想我们的事...
So you still think about us...
我们在一起
together?
嗯 有时心里难免会想
Well, it's crossed my mind from time to time.
然后呢？
And?
算了 我想过很多事情 埃文
Well, a lot of things have crossed my mind, Ev.
我是说一秒钟就可以想完我们的一生
I mean, I could play out the entire movie of our lives in one second.
嘣 恋爱 结婚 生子
Boom, we fall in love. We get married.
孩子长大 我们变老
We have kids. Our kids grow old, as do we.
准备葬礼... 诸如此类
Matching burial plots. The whole thing.
想象比说来得快
Plah, it took a lot longer to spit out than to imagine.
事情往往都这样
Things like that usually do.
这么说…
So...
你觉得我们有可能吗？
do you think that it might have worked?
当然
Yeah.
可是最终结果却不一样
I mean, but that's not how things wound up.
我现在跟兰尼在一起
I'm with Lenny.
兰尼是你的朋友
Lenny is your friend
而且...
and...
这就是结局
and that's where it ends.
喔...
Well...
是否结局会有所不同 如果我告诉你
would it make a difference if I told you that
我对你的爱世上没有人能比得上？
no one could possibly ever love anyone as much as I love you?
你别介意... 说这些... 我... 不...
I'm not saying that. I...
- 我明白 - 我只是说... 我说这些只是...
- Yeah. - I'm not... I'm just saying it like
如果你是个女孩 你会非常愿意
if you were a girl, would that be something
听到这些心里话
that you would want to hear?
稍等一会儿 兰尼叫我
Hold on one second. Lenny's calling.
我马上就会回来
I'll be right back, Ev, okay?
他情绪有点低落
He's a little down...
我爱你
I love you.
你忘了把脚趾放在水龙头上了
You forgot to put the toaster on the ledge.
兰尼现在生活很好
Lenny likes Pop Tarts.
你们现在都很好
You guys are all that matter now.
我知道这很艰难 可是你不能放弃
Man, I know it's hard, but you can't give up.
我他妈的连自杀都自杀不了
I can't even fucking kill myself.
你别这么说
Don't talk like that.
我得把你从这儿弄出来
Alright, I've got to get you out of here.
探视时间已经快过了
Visiting hours are almost over.
妈妈换了医院了吗？
Did Mum get transferred again?
你在说什么？她一直都在这里啊
What are you talking about? She's been here the entire time.
你看起来... 不错... 孩子
Looking... good, kiddo.
肺癌
Lung cancer.
肺癌？
Lung cancer?
我把自己炸伤以后 你就这样了
You started chain smoking when I blew myself up.
对不起 他最近很怪
Sorry, Mrs. T, he's been acting out of sorts lately.
- 我想我能修补的 - 修补？
- I think I could fix this. - Fix?
我只需要看我写的日记
I just need the journal entry about the blockbuster.
我没有手
Shit, no arms.
我从没写过
I never wrote it.
你的举止和原来不一样了
You're... acting... different.
他现在是困难时期
No, he's just going through tough times right now.
妈妈
Mum...
你会没有事的
you're going to be okay.
我可以改变这一切
I can change it.
我也许应该到礼拜堂去一下
Um, maybe... I wanna go down to the chapel.
你的... 行为... 跟...
You're... acting...
你的父亲一模一样
just like your father.
他在我这个年纪的时候发了疯
Just 'cause he went crazy when he was my age,
不代表我也要发疯
doesn't mean I'm gonna go crazy, Mum.
你是怎么
How... did...
知道的？
you... know that?
你告诉我的
You told me...
家长日 记得吗？
on parent's weekend, remember?
不是我吗？
It wasn't me...
- 只是 - 是你
- Just... - or you.
就像詹森
Like... Jason.
你不用担心
You don't worry, Mum,
我会把你从这儿弄出去的 放心吧
I'm going to get you out of here. Okay?
不
No.
你再也不会疼痛了
You're not going to hurt anymore.
我会挽回一切的
I'm going to fix it.
不
No.
不要 不要
No, no.
你确定已经把它们收起来了？
Are you sure you even packed it?
是我妈妈收的
My mum packed it.
我让她从家里寄来的
I think she sent everything I ever owned.
- 是这本吗？- 是的
- Is this it? - Yeah.
你找它想做什么？最近总是搞不懂你
What do you want it for? I don't get you lately.
你会明白的
Duly noted.
好了 你要帮我最后一个忙
Okay, I have to ask you one last favour.
- 什么事？- 请保持安静
- What? - I need you to be quiet.
我要集中精力毁掉那根雷管
I have to concentrate if I wanna destroy the blockbuster.
- 什么？大爆炸？- 如果我的手没有在那次爆炸中被炸掉
- What? What, the blockbuster? - If I hadn't blown off my arms,
我妈妈肯定永远不会染上烟瘾的
my mum would've never started smoking in the first place.
别想了 只管帮我打开日记
Never mind. Just open it.
翻页
Turn it.
好了 就这儿
There.
"今天妈妈会带我去
"Today Mummy is taking me to play
与凯丽和汤米玩
with Kayleigh and Tommy.
我会见到他们的爸爸 看看到底一个真正的爸爸会是什么样"
I will meet their father and see what a real dad is like."
现在要怎么才能毁掉这颗雷管？
Now, how do I destroy the blockbuster?
埃文 你拿那把刀做什么？
Evan, what are you doing with that knife?
唉 这个不行 翻页
Well, that didn't work. Go on, turn it.
再翻 就这儿
Turn it. There.
"反正我不想参加那部电影
"I never wanted to be in the movie anyway.
天有些冷 我想穿上衣服
It was cold so I wanted to wear my clothes.
米勒先生把我的衣服脱掉"
But Mr. Miller made me take my shirt off."
这部分的故事是这样的
In this part of the story,
罗宾汉刚刚与玛丽安小姐结婚
Robin Hood has just married Maid Marian.
因而他们得接吻 还有诸如此类的事
And they have to kiss and stuff,
就像成年人那样
like grown-ups do.
等等 我需要皮带
Wait, I need my belt.
别去管皮带啦
Hey, don't even bother about a belt.
- 嗨 - 退后老色鬼
- Hey. - Back off, fuckbag.
真奇怪你怎么总是留不下一点印象呢
Amazing that word never fails to make an impression with you.
你应该放松 埃文
Easy does it, Evan.
别做个坏孩子
Don't be a bad boy or I'll tell your mother
不然我告诉你妈妈说 你是个不听话的小混球
what a naughty little shit you are.
那我就告诉儿童保护协会
And I'll tell Child Protective Services
你在这里拍儿童色情电影
about your little kiddie porn endeavours.
你再靠近 我把你的屁股炸烂
One step closer and I'll shove this up your arse.
那个很危险 会把你手炸掉的
Hey, that's dangerous. You could blow off your hand.
已经炸断过了
Been there, done that.
嘿
Hey!
- 火花 - 凯丽不
- Sparkler. - Kayleigh, no!
不 凯丽 不
No! Kayleigh, no!
嘿 老兄
Hey, man.
不错嘛 儿子
...good, kiddo.
我不得不送你到圣维尔学院...
I've got no choice but to commit you to Sunnyvale Institution...
埃文 你要去另外一个地方呆一段时间
You're gonna have to live somewhere else for a while.
- 一只压碎的蝴蝶 - 我想要妈妈
- A squashed butterfly. - I want my mummy!
我实在受不了这些了
I'm so sick of this!
我想应该增加你的药物剂量
I think we should up your medication.
我的那些该死的书呢？
Where are my goddamn books?
埃文 我们应该一个小时后才见面
Hey, Evan, we're not supposed to meet for another hour.
我的那些该死的书呢？
Where are my goddamn books?
书？
Books?
我的日记
My journals.
我... 我需要它们
L... I need them.
因此 把它们给我 它们对我很有用
So, if you'd give 'em to me, it'd help a lot.
真伤心 你又来了
It really hurts me to go through this again.
没有日记
There are no journals.
从来就没有过那些日记
There never were.
这只是你的大脑虚构出来的幻想世界的一部分
It's part of the fantasy world that your mind created
用来克服你内心对误杀凯丽·米勒的内疚
to cope with the guilt of killing Kayleigh Miller.
想想吧 埃文 好好想想
Think, Evan, think.
你自己杜撰了一种根本就不存在的病
You've created a disease that does not exist...
交错活在大学
alternate universes with colleges
监狱和半身不遂的世界里
and prisons and paraplegia.
我要我的日记 现在就要
I want my journals and I want 'em now!
我知道它们在你手里 你必须把它们还给我
And I know that you got 'em and you're gonna give 'em to me!
你不要再骗我了 我需要它们
You're not going to hide them from me. I want them!
你让我想起了你父亲
You're reminding me of your father.
他总是大声喊叫要那些相簿
He was always screaming for a photo album
尽管那些相簿从来就没有存在过
even though he never had one.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我不是...
I'm not...
相簿？
A photo album?
- 相片 - 埃文？
- Photos. - Evan?
损伤是不可恢复性的
The damage is irreparable.
坦白地说 我真的感到惊奇 他的多项功能还能用
Frankly, I'm surprised he still has use of his motor functions.
妈妈
Mum?
嗯... 记得把我们
Um, did you remember to bring
过去拍的家庭电影带来了吗？
those home movies that we used to make?
带来了 就在这儿呢
Yeah, they're right here.
太好了 我真的喜欢看
Good, because I really like to watch them.
这真的太好了
So that's good.
我想最好明天一早
I think it's best we transfer him to Bellevue
就转到贝尔坞医院去
first thing in the morning.
"如果有人找到这封信
"If anyone finds this,
那就意味着我的计划不起作用...
it means that my plan didn't work...
并且我已经死了"
and I'm already dead."
他不在自己的房间里 仔细搜查整个一楼
He's not in his room. Search the grounds.
"如果我能以某种方式... 回到...
"If I can somehow go back...
所有这一切的... 开端
to the beginning of all of this...
我应该可以拯救她"
I might be able to save her."
埃文
Evan
去那里
Go there!
埃文
Evan
詹森 别拍啦 我快生了
I'm trying to have a baby.
走开
Go away.
啊
AH...
有点不对劲
Something's wrong!
疼死我了
It's killing me!
让他停下来 哦
Make it stop! Oh!
心跳在加速
Heart rate is decelerating.
发生什么事了？
What's happening?!
你没有生命线 没有灵魂 你根本就不该来到这个世上
You have no lifeline, no soul. You were never meant to be.
他快窒息了
He's choking himself!
不
No!
好吧 我们给她做剖腹产 准备
Okay, let's do a rapid sequence intubation for a c-section, stat!
- 救救他 - 氧气不足
- Save him! - Not getting enough oxygen!
- 他快不行了不行了 - 不
- We're losing him, we're losing him! - No!
在你出生前
Before you were born,
我怀孕了三次
I was pregnant three times,
但他们都流产了
but they were all stillbirths.
从那时候开始我认为你是我的奇迹小宝宝
I've kind of thought of you as my miracle baby ever since.
不要了
Not again!
不要
No!
我受不了我爸爸
I couldn't stand my dad,
但如果我和我妈妈一起住
but I knew that if I went to live with my mum,
我就再也见不到你了
I would never see you again.
凯丽 汤米
Kayleigh and Tommy!
我好想你们
I missed you!
我再也不会让你们离开我了
I'll never let you guys out of my sight again.
吔
Yeah!
只有做出牺牲才能获得幸福
True happiness can only be achieved through sacrifice,
就像我们父母一样 他们做出巨大牺牲 我们才有今日
like the sacrifices our parents have made, to make us be here today!
哇哦 太棒了 汤米
Whoo-hoo! Great! Tommy!